



Daniele Giardiello

Nationality: Italian (+39) 3476731205 **Date of birth:** 28/11/1988 **Gender:** Male

Email address: daniele.giardiello1@gmail.com

Website: https://danielegiardiello.github.io/

• Address: (Italy)

ABOUT ME

Statistician | Data scientist with robust experience in research and statistical consulting in various international research institutes and private companies. R / SAS / STATA / Python programmer with strong passion in data science and statistics. Extremely curious to actively know new skills through challenging learning and working in team.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Biomedical data scientist / Biostatistician (home-based)

EURAC research [06/04/2021 - 31/07/2022]

- https://www.eurac.edu/en

City: Bolzano/Bozen

Country: Italy

Biomedical data scientist and statistical consultant in the field of biomedical research. Contract till July 2022.

PhD candidate - PhD defence on 8th September 2022

The Netherlands Cancer Institute (NKI) and Leiden University Medical Center (LUMC) [15/11/2016 – 28/02/2021]

Address: (Netherlands) - https://www.nki.nl/divisions/molecular-pathology/schmidt-m-group/

City: Amsterdam **Country:** Netherlands

Name of unit or department: Molecular Pathology (in NKI), Biomedical data sciences (in LUMC) - Business or

sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities

Main goal: to develop, validate and assess the prediction performance and the clinical utility of a contralateral breast cancer risk prediction model using time-to-event models with competing risks using individual patient data (more than 100,000 patients) from multiple studies in presence of sporadic and systematic missing data.

Main activities:

- Data management and R/SAS/STATA programming also using High Performance Computing (HPC);
- Experience in Real World Data coming from different international sources;
- · Reading scientific literature especially about applied biostatistics and risk prediction modelling;
- Statistical consulting for researchers and statistical teaching;
- Writing peer review scientific manuscripts;
- Provide statistical reports using Rmarkdown and GitHub.

Supervisors: prof. Marjanka K Schmidt and prof. Ewout W Steyerberg

Statistician

OPIS srl [01/07/2016 - 30/09/2016]

Address: 20832 Desio (Monza and Brianza) (Italy) - https://opisresearch.com/

City: Desio Country: Italy

- Business or sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities

Overall description: biostatistician working in clinical trials (phase II-III).

Main activities:

SAS programming; Revising Case Report Forms (CRFs); Providing listings, figures, and tables.

Statistician

Italian National Cancer Institute [09/2014 - 06/2016]

Address: 20133 Milan (Italy) - https://www.istitutotumori.mi.it/en/home

City: Milan **Country:** Italy

Name of unit or department: Clinical Epidemiology and Clinical Trials organization - Business or sector:

Professional, scientific and technical activities

- Statistical consulting in medical research;
- R/SAS programming;
- Supporting research in statistical medical writing;

Statistician

The Lombardy and Emilia Romagna Experimental Zootechnic Institute [04/2013 - 09/2014]

Address: 25124 Brescia (Italy) - https://www.izsler.it/

City: Brescia **Country:** Italy

- Business or sector: Professional, scientific and technical activities
 - Statistical consulting and support for veterinary research;
 - Epidemiological surveillance;
 - Spatial statistics;

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Doctor of Philosophy, PhD

Leiden University Medical Center [14/11/2016 – 28/02/2021]

Address: Leiden (Netherlands) https://www.universiteitleiden.nl/en

Thesis: Title of the dissertation: "Prediction of contralateral breast cancer - Statistical aspects and performance

assessment"

My dissertation is available here

MSc in Biostatistics and Experimental Statistics (summa cum laude)

University of Milan - Bicocca [10/2010 – 11/2012]

Address: Milan (Italy) https://en.unimib.it/

BSc in Statistical Science and information management (summa cum laude)

University of Milan - Bicocca [10/2007 - 09/2010]

Address: Milan (Italy) https://en.unimib.it/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Italian

Other language(s):

English Dutch

LISTENING C1 READING C1 WRITING C1 LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION C1 SPOKEN INTERACTION C1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

DIGITAL SKILLS

My Digital Skills

R / SAS / STATA / SPSS software / SQL / R Markdown / GitHUB / Basic of Python

PUBLICATIONS

List of all publications in pubmed

https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/?term=daniele+giardiello&sort=date&size=100

DRIVING LICENCE

Driving Licence: B

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Hobbies and interests

Running (middle-distance track and field athlete), nature, music, hospital clowning